# **Tamlin Love**

tamlinlove.github.io | GitHub | LinkedIn | Email: tamlinlollislove@gmail.com

Barcelona, Spain

Barcelona, Spain

2023 - Present

2020 - 2021

2016 - 2018

# **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

I am a young researcher from South Africa, now working as a PhD student at the Institut de Robotica i Informàtica Industrial (IRI) (under CSIC and UPC) in Barcelona, working on the TRAIL MSCA-DN project. I am passionate about the possibilities for humans and artificial agents to communicate, collaborate and learn from each other. To that end, I am interested in areas where human knowledge can augment an agent's abilities (e.g. human-in-the-loop, interactive RL) and where human-agent collaboration and communication can improve the human experience (e.g. human-robot interaction, social robotics, explainability). More broadly, I am also interested in the ethical, explainable and safe applications of these technologies.

## **EDUCATION**

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya

PhD in Automatic Control, Robotics and Computer Vision

University of the Witwatersrand

Johannesburg, South Africa

Master of Science in Computer Science (with distinction)

University of the Witwatersrand Johannesburg, South Africa

Bachelor of Science Honours in Computer Science (with distinction)

University of the Witwatersrand Johannesburg, South Africa

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (with distinction)

St John's College Johannesburg, South Africa

Matric (8 distinctions) 2015

Member of the <u>Perception and Manipulation</u> group at the <u>Institut de Robòtica i Informàtica Industrial</u> from 2023 - present. Member of the Robotics, Autonomous Intelligence and Learning (RAIL) from 2020 - 2023.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

For a complete list, please follow this link.

# Who should I trust? Cautiously learning with unreliable experts

2022

Tamlin Love, Ritesh Ajoodha, Benjamin Rosman

Neural Computing and Applications

**Masters Thesis** 

Featured at RLDM 2022 and HARL Workshop @ ICDL 2021

# **Building Undirected Influence Ontologies Using Pairwise Similarity Functions**

2020

Tamlin Love, Ritesh Ajoodha

International SAUPEC/RobMech/PRASA Conference

Honours Research Project

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Researcher**Institut de Robòtica i Informàtica Industrial
Barcelona, Spain

titat ac Robotica i illioi illatica illaastilat

- Working on the TRAIL: TRAnsparent InterpretabLe robots project (project code: HORIZON-MSCA-DN-101072488), a Marie Skłodowska-Curie Doctoral Network project funded by the European Union.
- Involves research on explainability, causality, human-robot interaction, and robot perception.
- Includes extensive use of Python and ROS.

**Sessional Lecturer**University of the Witwatersrand
Johannesburg, South Africa

- Managed and taught the 3rd year Software Design courses and co-taught the 1st year Basic Computer Organisation course for the Computer Science undergraduate degree
- Set, oversaw and marked practical and theoretical assessments for the above courses

Backend Developer 2021 – 2022

BodyBack Johannesburg,South Africa

• Created and maintained the REST backend framework for the BodyBack mobile application

**Tutor** 2018 – 2021

University of the Witwatersrand

Johannesburg, South Africa

• Tutored a number of computer science and applied mathematics courses for undergraduate and honours students

# PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE

**Languages** : Python, Java, C, C++, Matlab

I have experience working with robots (TurtleBot, Kuri by Mayfield Robotics, and RealAnt by OTE) and with the robotics operating system (ROS).

# **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

# **Organisation**

- "Robot Learning for Africa Workshop" at the Deep Learning Indaba in Ghana, 2023 (Website)
- "From Specialists to Generalists: The World of Generalised RL Agents" workshop at the Deep Learning Indaba in Tunisia, 2022 (Website)

## **Workshops and Summer Schools**

- EASE Fall School, Bremen, Germany 2023
- Deep Learning Indaba, Tunis, Tunisia 2022
- HARL Workshop @ ICDL 2021

#### Reviewing

UniReps Workshop @ Neurlps 2023, ICSR 2023, ICRA 2023, NeurlPS 2022

## Languages

- English (home language)
- Italian (conversational)
- Spanish (basic)

# **ACADEMIC AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS**

## 2022

Poster award at the Deep Learning Indaba 2022

#### 2021

Post-graduate merit award scholarship

#### 2020

Post-graduate merit award scholarship

## 2019

Post-graduate merit award scholarship

Dean's list

#### 2018

Dean's list

Liberty Life Gold Medal for outstanding performance in Computer Science

Prize for Top Student in Computational & Applied Mathematics

Herbert Le May Prize for the best 3rd year science student majoring in Applied Mathematics

Placed 2nd in the SAMMC competition for mathematical modelling

First class certificates for 4 courses, merit certificate for 1 course

# 2017

Dean's list

Psybergate Computer Science prize

First class certificates for 3 courses, merit certificates for 6 courses

# 2016

Dean's list